hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft and
you might be wondering why i'm wearing
this rather fabulous and snazzy looking
gold armor it does actually look really
good with the new texture i got to say
it looks rather formidable well it will
become very clear why i'm wearing this
in a very short amount of time but
there's a few things to show you with
the bass so obviously the flag is coming
down very shortly and
we're still not quite ready this is
probably the last episode
before the war actually begins so we've
got a lot of preparation to do before
everything kicks off and
there's a few blaring holes in the in
the base and it's not just this one i'm
making here it's that we don't actually
have an entrance yet we don't actually
have a front door at the moment we've
been using it
well he was taken care of so this is the
entrance that we've been using
pretty much the entire time that we've
been building this thing and you'll see
that there's actually some decorations
in here now we've added some lighting on
the roof which or the ceiling which is
basically end rods just hanging at
different lengths it looked really
really nice in my opinion it looks quite
nice and you'll see all of these cases
full of armor stands as a bit of
decoration so you can see that this room
was very bare before it's still kind of
bare but it's it's nice enough to be
a lobby of its own kind of thing and
this is exactly
why i'm wearing the gold armor because i
need to show you an idea so to decorate
this room zombie glio decided to put in
a bunch of arm stands which is really
really cool but there's some intentional
spaces that have been left clear that's
because
if we're up in the control center and we
see an attack incoming if we see them
like running across the field and we're
like oh no oh no oh no oh no and we run
down what we're able to do is hide in
plain sight and then scare them off if
they think that they're safe so the idea
that we put together is that we take an
invisibility potion
and we go and hide among these and you
cannot tell the difference unless you
see the particles which is why there's a
space up there which would be less
obvious so if we go behind here
in a panic this is all in a rush we run
up here and we drink the invisibility
potion as we go along we have to break
in and we resume our space here now it's
very important that once we've drunk the
potion we have nothing in our hands not
in the off hand nothing so it'll give us
a way and then we have to stand very
very still like this so what we're going
to do is i'm going to tell iskall to
come and meet me so that we can test
this out for ourselves because he
doesn't know what all of this is he has
no idea so i'm going to type to him now
so i said iskall can i get your help
with the front door in the lobby and
then we'll see how this goes now this
invisibility potion works for eight
minutes so i think i'm pretty safe to
drink it now okay he's coming right now
there he is where are you
hello did i just imagine you talking
what is going on i'm here i'm in the
room can you see me
yes
dude what is going on
what is going on i think maybe my client
oh dude
wow what
oh bro that's genius man did you really
not see me i did not see you dude i was
looking for green not an armor style
can you see the particles around me how
obvious is it no i don't see them hold
on i think i may have them switched off
in optifine
that would explain a lot yeah they're
they're off okay yeah i do see but
they're white though to be fair okay
hold on let me go back up there and you
tell me how obvious it is so my idea
here iskall is
when they come
and attack us we quickly run up here we
assume positions with an invisibility
potion and we stand guard if i stand
completely still how obvious is it there
is no way i can see the particles from
here unless i zoom in and know exactly
which armor standard is but the arm the
the particles from the end rods actually
makes it very oh my god this is so bad
brilliant that's brilliant you are a
weird person green i don't like it
i gotta be honest this is one of the
spookiest things i've ever seen dude but
it's just
imagine that there's like four of us so
me up there and then like a couple of
people just standing here like this
they'll never see her coming
no
that's incredible
and then we just take it all off and
it's just
yeah see this is this is all so scary
just a flying trident
[Laughter]
anyway that's not the reason that i i
kind of baited you here with the reason
for the front door we do actually need a
front door though because we've been
using this hole the whole time
yeah i see what you did there yeah well
done
but yeah the the war is coming very soon
iskow and we're definitely not finished
in this base we don't even have an
entrance i mean no yeah
we don't have a front door which isn't a
bad thing but we have been working on a
few things
underneath the base obviously we've like
decorated in here a bit but i think
that's about as much as we're gonna do
here
i mean i like i like this room a lot
more than what it was before i looked at
it earlier today and and yeah it looks
really sick well the thing is we don't
have a lot of time to make a lot of
things we've got we've got like 10
things we need to build but not enough
time to do them so we're gonna have to
cut corners massively to get everything
done in time exactly and no one really
cares about a door i mean it's only yeah
exactly as long as as long as it's like
uh some sort of secret entrance to open
it then it's fine yeah but the other
thing that we really need to do is
vaults we need to hide our stuff because
like this guy i don't know if you've
seen but if you go into our storage room
it went from being quite organized to an
absolute mess it's terrible oh my
terrible
like all of these chests are now full of
junk that these there are even more
shelter boxes than
yeah that was here yeah that was me
there's shulker boxes everywhere just
full of random junk
and one of these there's no point in
even labeling these anymore because
there's just nothing like
whatever it is bad
i got something to show you
i've been working all day on on votes on
vaults
vaults in plural we also need an
entrance down to the base like look at
this it's just down
it's just a hole in the floor and you
fall in you got to check this out though
i'm super happy to to show you this so i
have actually put up three volts here
three is one not enough no we don't want
to make it too easy for me come on okay
all right
that feels a lot that feels very 2018.
these walls are actually finished i just
completed them so they require a key
code a key card and i have made a
several amounts of key cards for the
base the star team has to figure out
which key card goes to which door
that's the first task if they would want
to break in here
you got it
look at that yeah so is this where all
the chests go yeah so you come in here
you pull the lever in the middle
[Music]
there's nothing in here right this is a
this is a red herring
so this is this is let me get this
straight this isn't a real volt the real
vault is one of those two
no they're cake vaults as well
they are exact they are also cakeful
it's a it's a wild goose chase okay so
where's where is the the vault
yeah about that um
i haven't really got that far yet do you
want me to make the the real vault
the vault that we actually hide stuff in
that would be very helpful actually yeah
i did i did think about a position over
here
okay
where they're absolutely expecting it to
be i'm just gonna mark out the three by
three door and then give me a little bit
of space here green because i have done
redstone for you in the past yeah and i
leave you with zero space
yeah so maybe start the vault here
all right
you got it boss i've made a pretty
decent start on this but no there was
tragedy tragedy and i was saved by
iskall actually so i was like mining
along here minding my own business like
so and i fell like just like that into
here which actually was full of lava now
i actually cheated death i wasn't even
recording i was just mining away and i i
dug straight down guys i just went
landed in love i went
and i logged out at absolute top speed
and then the iskal then quickly got
about 14 messages that said let's go
let's go help help help
i was so convinced i was like i was
gonna die honestly so he came and then
he uh got rid of all the lava and i
cheated death just by locking out we've
all done it before oh my goodness i'm so
glad because there's no way i could get
all of these tools back you realize that
if you die in lava and you lose all
these items you have to spend about an
hour getting all that stuff back anyway
i've made some good progress here this
is currently the vault situation and
you'll see that there's a very strange
ceiling and these are actually cauldrons
and i've got to admit
this was very expensive i think this was
several stacks of iron blocks to get
this made but it should look more
reinforced i just love it when you put
some sea lanterns in here and if you
space them quite nicely you get this
really cool effect where it's around
there i've shown this in a video before
but in case you haven't seen it it's a
really cool technique and cauldrons
actually are really resistant to
explosions so it kind of makes it a bit
more reinforced in here as well but we
shouldn't have that problem because
they're not going to be able to get in
the door there we go that's actually
really cool lighting i need to fix this
hole this is exactly how i ended up with
lava so i think i'm going to leave most
of this space in the middle open
and then have i might even have secret
rooms within this room so on the off
chance that they managed to get in here
via our very cool system of whatever we
decided to do
uh i think we should have rooms within
like a vault within the vault vault
section
we've got so many vaults at the moment
that
i don't think they'll ever actually
believe that we have a real one at this
point however i think if we have a
secret vault within the vault with some
actual
goodies so like maybe this one has stuff
that we don't care about so cobblestone
andersite all of the junk that we seem
to have accumulated over building this
base and then we have the real vault
where we keep our tnt our redstone all
of the very valuable things there's a
particular box that i need to look after
the most and it's this gray box because
it's full
of my very favorite friend pufferfish
paul
and we're going to be using those a
little later on in the war we can't use
them right now the thing is i don't want
to go ahead and start trapping
all of the base because well you guys
will see it they'll see it and then the
whole thing gets spoiled now obviously
we're not going to be just going in and
griefing everyone's base that's not how
this works it's not how this whole thing
is going to play out so let's say that
they've built a vault of their own and
they've made a way to get into it it
would be so easy for me to just go boop
boop boop boop
and i'm in your vault this isn't a
faction server this is hermitcraft so if
they've built a vault with a wall you
know with a door and redstone and stuff
i'm gonna figure out how to get in there
the way that they've designed it you
know because that's the cool way to do
it and that's the sort of rule set that
we're going to be applying it would be
so easy for us to go into their base and
blow the whole thing up with tnt and say
war done and same for them they could
just launch a million blocks of tnt war
over right so we're trying to have the
most fun possible with this and do
things that we wouldn't normally do in
minecraft especially on hermitcraft so
that's something to bear in mind okay
i think this is coming along quite
nicely and unfortunately it's going to
be a pretty
pretty dull build i'm not going to lie
it's just going to be a secure room with
a bunch of chests in it because i'm not
even going to be doing the redstone in
here i think that's going to be mainly
iskow so
yeah looks like i'm just going to grind
away at this
so this is what one side will look like
and hopefully it will just be a replica
all the way around so this is very much
just a grind there's nothing really to
this apart from like
we're making these rooms seem extra
pretty and stuff but realistically this
is just a storage room but it's it's
still got to look nice because we've put
so much effort in absolutely everywhere
so
pretty much just lots and lots and lots
of chests
we could try and decorate it with a
couple of paintings or something i
really don't know need to try and do
something at the back here maybe some
end rod featuring
and then put a painting inside here
maybe not that one
which one's the nicest maybe that blue
skull works the best yeah it kind of
goes with the whole blue theme yeah i
kind of like that it gives it a little
bit more detail
oh man i'm really
got to admit this is a bit of a chore
but once this is done we'll finally have
somewhere to put all of our stuff and
that room of junk up there will finally
be sorted so we need a place for all of
our shulker boxes as well because most
of it is in shulker boxes and i
definitely don't want to be the one that
has to sort through all that stuff so
maybe these two sides are chests so
they're going to be mimicked and then
this one here can be for all of the
various shulker boxes i think that's
where i'm going to leave the vault for
now i'm going to finish this off off
camera and maybe show you in the next
episode because my oh my have i had
enough of building this but it's coming
along rather well you can really tell
what this is going to end up looking
like there's going to be chests on the
other side there's going to be shulker
boxes all over the place here but at
least it will be slightly bigger and
more organized and it looks pretty cool
in my opinion but there's plenty of
other things to do and i actually want
to give you guys a quick tour of the
base so you can get your bearings for
what is to come
so obviously this is the underground
lobby we've got a couple of rooms in
here we've got potion dispenser but the
one thing that i haven't really shown
you is this which is our food farm
instead of getting a normal like potato
or carrot farm we're actually going to
be farming up some sheep so we've got a
bunch of wheat we breed them leave them
to do their business
and then once they've gone they drop
into here after you press this button
there we go
and then they become adults and we just
gotta wait for that
uh and then we've actually got a sword
here which has fire aspect on it and
bam
we get some cooked mutton and some wool
which is good for the infinite amount of
beds we're going to probably need when
you need a couple more you hit this
button and it pushes them through but i
haven't actually left a lot of time for
those to become adults so that might
have been a really bad idea but then
they come up this year like they're like
printing sheep and up they come and you
got more so unfortunately we got a few
babies in there so i'll leave those to
grow but you get the idea and then we
put the sword back where it was and
that's our food farm and i've got myself
some mutton here to chomp on this is our
aquarium where jevin has actually put in
some armor stands which is pretty cool
doesn't really serve any other purpose
than to leave the building this room
should be completely empty by the time
we're ready and we've got ourselves some
horses which we're going to take into
battle and it looks like i'm stuck with
the donkey
and upstairs we have our dangerous
control room which actually i added
something off camera again is a big old
map of everything so i figure that most
of the stuff on the outside is now
complete so i put together this little
map is obviously not quite finished on
that side because it was really
bothering me that it wasn't centered so
i added this line but i never got around
to it but yeah we've got a map so we can
see the battlefield
and we've got all of our secret weapons
some of which you know about and some
that you don't
and up here we have the meeting room
where we've actually captured
a friend
something that i wish i'd never seen
ever again after the hunt of all of
these but here we are iskall actually
captured this and i think we might
capture a few more to use to our
advantage in the future but he's kind of
screaming at the moment so i think we
should silence him got myself a name tag
and
how do i name him
i can't i can't actually click him
can you even name these
does he have to be out of the minecart
how does this even work
no this is this is a terrible idea yeah
he's i'm clicking in the best i can on
unless he's like glitch through
i don't think i can get him
i guess we'll just leave that here
and i'll ask someone that knows what
they're doing with these guys so i don't
die to them so that's pretty much the
base as it stands we still don't have an
official entrance but it looks like
iskall is working on that oh maybe he's
already done it
oh that is cool it doesn't leave you a
lot of time to get out
oh it doesn't leave you a lot of time at
all but that is really cool that is a
sweet entrance so we might be able to
cover this up now having said that i
don't actually know how you get in from
the outside all of these drones that
belong to concorp have sprouted up which
uh i guess they're like surveillance
drones or something but they look really
cool
oh i can't wait for all the builds to
pop up anyway there is a shop that has
popped up from cub fan or concorp is
that i don't want to know i don't want
to know
so concorp reserves the right to test
you your to test your war
uh oh your war readiness at any time if
you are ready then enter enjoy the store
so i actually do want to buy some
potions and stuff and see what else he's
got in here but i have actually been
warned that something might happen if i
go in i don't know what
anything
i think i'm safe oh does that mean i am
i'm tried and tested
okay
elixir of all betsy free you know what i
am gonna take a couple of milk buckets
because that seems like a good idea what
i want is some of these
i kind of want to know what happens if
you if you do get tested
dare i
i think there's a
this is ridiculous i can't get attacked
even if i ask it to okay one more try
and if it doesn't work that's it i'm i'm
totally worthy of this shop
but it's probably just gonna do it the
one time that i actually want it nope
it's definitely not working that's fine
i i don't want to die anyway i was told
that you probably will die
but i don't
oh great of course
it does it when i leave
is it just angry music
it's just angry music
[Music]
ah no it's not no it's not it's these
guys the guys okay okay okay okay okay
okay yep
i guess that's why it's called convex
right because of the fx's so you got to
leave the shot basically if that guy
goes off you've got to leave the shop
because those things those things hurt
all right so now we know if you go in
there and the alarm goes off you get
swarmed by a bunch of vexes but
apparently i'm pretty worthy because it
just didn't want to go off but i've also
been thinking about what i'm going to do
in my own base
after this war is all done and dusted
and the answer is i'm not really too
sure
you see i want to do a few things i want
to
actually finish decorating it like these
bits here obviously need to go on the
back tower there however
i'm just so lazy this is such a dull
task to do i really can't be bothered
but one of the big projects that i do
want to do after this is all done
is build the train station for our
district miner mumbo's little area
right here in the middle it's something
i talked about before but never really
got the opportunity to start so that's
probably the next project
after this war is all done and dusted
and of course i still need to fix up or
well fill
two layers of my base but i still have
no idea what that might be
but other than that i'm afraid that's
all we have time for today most of the
work that i've been doing over the last
few days have been making secret
projects and
you just finishing off this base this is
like a full season's worth of
hermitcraft base right here and it's
been mostly built by me iscout and
stress so it's been extraordinarily
a lot like difficult to get all of this
work done in time for the deadline
i don't know how to get in so i'm just
gonna have to break in
but i'm very excited
this is all
brand new to me and i really hope we
have a lot of fun thank you very much
for watching everyone and keep an eye
out for that team star for me because
it's all going down
very soon good bye